We're expecting you to already be familiar with object-oriented programming, and
to have experience with Java or a similar language.
Personally, I got started with Android after years of Delphi and C# development.
As engineers, we're trained to map our experiences in one language or
SDK into new ones. Looking for patterns and shortcuts we can get up to
speed as quickly as possible. But mobile, and Android in particular,
have some fundamental differences that mean some of our experience and
intuition will actually make us worse mobile engineers. We like to think of
Smartphones as computers that fit into our pockets. In a way that's true, but
the computers from the 90s, like this Powerhouse I was using nearly 20
years ago. With limited internet connectivity, low speed CPUs, and limited RAM,
on top of which, they're all running on batteries. As we go through the course,
I'll be returning to each of these key mobile challenges. Looking for
places where you're experienced on desktop or
server, or even other mobile platforms might lead you in the wrong direction.
I will also be back to tell you some stories from the early days of Android.
Stories that describe how the Android platform has evolved. And nowhere is
that more readily apparent than here, at the Android Lawn sculpture garden.
Join me here, at the very heart of Android, at the end of this lesson,
to find out how this sculpture garden of tasty treats, also tell us the story of
Android's history. For now, let's get back to building that weather app.
So, we'll cross to Dan, to take a look at some mocks.